Buğra Önal Cellph: (831) 251-9923

onalbugra@gmail.com • https://www.linkedin.com/in/bugra-onal-a00492b9/

SUMMARY

Experience in SoC and FPGA development and verification • RTL design with Verilog and VHDL • Proficient in Modelsim, Verilator Xilinx tools (ISE, Vivado, Vivado HLS, Vivado SDK) • Coding skills in C, modern C++, Python, Java, MATLAB, UNIX scripting, Qt Framework • Experience in Raspberry Pi development, OpenCV, Boost, Django libraries • TAship experience • VLSI design (Magic, IRSIM, Netgen) • OpenRAM

EDUCATION

PhD in CSE, September 2021 - Present, University of California Santa Cruz, Santa Cruz, USA

MS in EE, September 2019 - September 2021, Özyeğin University, Istanbul, Turkey (GPA: 3.50/4.00)

Thesis involves implementing an area efficient static memory allocation/synthesis method within a compiler of a synthesized soft-core CPU. Funded by TÜBİTAK.

BS in EE & CS (double major), August 2019, Özyeğin University, Istanbul, Turkey (GPA: 3.56/4.00)

Senior Project on Parametrized FPGA Video Flow Design.

EMPLOYMENT

Graduate Assistant at Özyeğin University, Istanbul, Turkey, September 2019 - Present

TA'ed the following courses: Python for Engineers, Digital Electronics and FPGA Design, Computer Architecture

Software Development and Testing Engineer at SemiMobility, Istanbul, Turkey, October 2019 - Present

Developed FPGA IPs for Electric Motor Drives. Did RTL design, verification, and synthesis. Also helped other team members in bring-up.

Intern Hardware Designer at Matriks Data, July 2019 - August 2019

Implemented "Limit Order Book" algorithms on FPGA using High Level Synthesis as part of a High Frequency Trading (HFT) hardware/software solution.

Intern Hardware Designer at Yonga Technology Microelectronics R&D, June 2018 - June 2019

Worked in tandem with the company for my senior project on parametrized video flow algorithm implementations on FPGA.

PROJECTS

OpenRAM (October 2021 – Present): Active contributor to open-source static random access memory (SRAM) compiler. The project is led by Prof. Guthaus and funded by Google.

Static Memory Allocation for a Synthesized Soft-Core CPU (April 2020 – September 2021): Improving a Clang based C compiler for a custom CPU called VerySimpleCPU (VSCPU). This project is funded by TÜBİTAK (Turkish NSF). VSCPU was designed by Prof. H. Fatih Uğurdağ's team. It has a small instruction set, which has "instruction set completeness". The improvement to the compiler involves adding a static memory allocation instead of emulating a stack. Since VSCPU does not have stack-based instructions, a statically memory mapped application has smaller program and data memory footprint.

Virtual FPGA Board (September 2020 – June 2021): An FPGA board simulator intended to be used in distance education, developed using Verilator. A GUI was designed using Qt framework. The GUI replicates a typical FPGA board with virtual LEDs, push buttons, switches, and a seven-segment display. The GUI and the Verilator model communicate through UDP packets.

High Frequency Electric Motor Control IP (August 2019 - Present): The IP controls BLDC motors on Xilinx Zynq SoCs. This project was funded by TÜBİTAK. Designed RTL modules running on Zynq PL. Conducted component level simulation tests and system level FPGA-in-the-Loop verification in MATLAB. Wrote a software for monitoring/controlling the motors, running on the Zynq PS. Developed Qt based desktop application, communicating with the Zynq FPGA.

Automatic Door Locking System (February 2020 - June 2020): A web application with scheduled and on-request locking/unlocking system using a Raspberry Pi. The application supports a calendar view showing the schedule of a door. The app. supports multiple doors. The doors can be opened manually utilizing face recognition or automatically when the scheduled time arrives. The app. utilizes a database for keeping track of the schedules and users.

High Frequency Trading on FPGA using HLS (July 2019 - August 2019): This is an implementation of the "Limit Order Book" algorithm for HFT on an FPGA equipped NIC using HLS. The program using Xilinx Vivado HLS. The algorithm utilizes a heap structure for keeping track of orders. Buyer and seller orders are matched as fast as possible according to their prices.

Parametrized FPGA Video Flow (September 2018 - June 2019): A set of parametrized video processing algorithms implemented on an FPGA. The algorithms include histogram equalization, median filter, and fish-eye lens distortion correction. Project was done in cooperation with Yonga Technology Microelectronics R&D and Prof. H. Fatih Uğurdağ.

Laser Object Tracking (February 2018 - June 2018): A Raspberry Pi application that tracks an object and points a laser pointer at it. The project utilized OpenCV library and was written in Python.

PUBLICATIONS

B. Tufekci, B. Onal, H. Dere, and H. F. Ugurdag, "Hardware Implementation of Field Oriented Control for Three Phase Machine Drives," 28th IEEE Signal Processing and Communications Applications Conference (SIU), Gaziantep, Turkey, October 2020.

B. Tufekci, B. Onal, H. Dere, and H. F. Ugurdag, "Efficient FPGA Implementation of Field Oriented Control for 3-Phase Machine Drives," 18th IEEE East-West Design & Test Symposium (EWDTS), Varna, Bulgaria, September 2020.

MISCELLANEOUS

Ranked 3rd in IEEEXtreme 14.0 programming competition (October 2020) among contestants from Turkey

TOEFL iBT score of 111 out of 120 (August 2019)

Top ranking student in the class of 2019 within BSEE and BSCS majors

Ranked 9th in IEEEXtreme 12.0 programming competition (October 2018) among contestants from Turkey

Page: 1 of 1

Print Date:



*** UNOFFICIAL ***

Name: Önal, Bugra Student ID: 1927019

Institution Info:

University of California, Santa Cruz 1156 High Street Santa Cruz, CA 95064

Beginning of Graduate Record

2021 Fall Quarter

Program: Plan: Course CSE 200 CSE 220 CSE 297A	Computer Science & Engineer PhD in Computer Science and Engineering Description Research & Teaching Comp Architecture Individual Study	Attempted 3.00 5.00 5.00	Earned 3.00 5.00 5.00	Grade S A S	Points 0.000 20.000 0.000
Academic Standing Effective 12/17/2021: Good Standing					
Term GPA Transfer Term GPA Combined GPA Cum GPA Transfer Cum GPA Combined Cum GPA	 0.00 Term Totals Transfer Totals 0.00 Comb Totals 0.00 Cum Totals Transfer Totals 0.00 Comb Totals 	Attempted 13.00 0.00 13.00 13.00 0.00 13.00 13.00	Earned 13.00 0.00 13.00 13.00 0.00 13.00	5.00 0.00 5.00 5.00 0.00 5.00 0.00 5.00	Points 20.000 0.000 20.000 20.000 0.000 20.000
2022 Winter Quarter					
Program: Plan:	Computer Science & Engineer PhD in Computer Science and Engineering				
Course CSE 201 CSE 222A	<u>Description</u> Analysis Algorithms Advanced VLSI	Attempted 5.00 5.00	Earned 0.00 0.00	<u>Grade</u>	Points 0.000 0.000
Term GPA Transfer Term GPA Combined GPA	0.00 Term Totals Transfer Totals 0.00 Comb Totals	Attempted 10.00 0.00 10.00	Earned 0.00 0.00 0.00	GPA Units 0.00 0.00 0.00	Points 0.000 0.000 0.000
Cum GPA Transfer Cum GPA Combined Cum GPA	0.00 Cum Totals Transfer Totals 0.00 Comb Totals	23.00 0.00 23.00	13.00 0.00 13.00	5.00 0.00 5.00	20.000 0.000 20.000
Graduate Career Totals Cum GPA: Transfer Cum GPA Combined Cum GPA	0.00 Cum Totals Transfer Totals 0.00 Comb Totals	23.00 0.00 23.00	13.00 0.00 13.00	5.00 0.00 5.00	20.000 0.000 20.000

End of *** UNOFFICIAL ***